Finding Aid for Washtenaw Rainbow Action Project Records 1993-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Events
  - Human Rights Campaign (HRC) Dinner
    - Memorandum of agreement with HRC and volunteer list 2002 (Box 14)
  - Michigan LGBT & Ally Leadership Summit -- The Peninsula Group 2007 (Box 14)
  - Michigan Pride 2003 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 2003-2007 (Box 14)
    - 2005 (Box 14)
  - OutFest (National Coming Out Day-NCOD)
    - 2001 (Box 14)
    - 2002 (Box 14)
    - 2003, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - 2003-2005 (Box 14)
    - 2003-2007 (Box 14)
    - 2004, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - 2005 (Box 14)
      (Contains photographs)
    - 2006 (Box 14)
    - 2008 (Box 14)
    - Archive 2001-2002 (Box 14)
    - Auction 2006 (Box 14)
    - Dinner 1997 (Box 14)
    - Donations 2006-2007 (Box 14)
    - Funds received 2004 (Box 14)
    - Raffle 2002 (Box 14)
    - Volunteer sign-in 2007 (Box 14)
  - Photographs 1999 (Box 14)
  - Pride Picnic
    - 2002 (Box 14)
    - 2003 (Box 14)
    - 2006 (Box 14)
  - Queer Summit
    - April 17, 2002 (Box 14)
    - April 17, 2002 April 3, 2003 (Box 14)
    - August 20, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Summer 2002 (Box 15)
  - The Experience Workshop June-July 2003 (Box 15)
  - Washtenaw pride 2004 (Box 15)
- Finance
  Grant and insurance information encapsulate the bulk of the Finance series (1 linear foot) records. Also of note in this series are the documents relevant to the organization's 501(c)(3) status, budget, and yearly financial reports.
  - 501(c)(3)
    - Appeal letter 1999 (Box 15)
    - Non-profit corporation update
      (records changes in the organization like new Board members)
      - 2002-2006 (Box 15)
      - 2003-2004 (Box 15)
    - Verification and articles of incorporation 1995-2002 (Box 15)
  - Audit goals and financial situation 2003 (Box 15)
    (organizational goals set by WRAP after an audit conducted by JSM in partner with the Gill Foundation)
  - Binder 1997-1998 (Box 15)
  - Budget
    - 2002-2003 (Box 15)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 15)
    - 2008 (Box 15)
  - Corporate sponsors 2000-2004 (Box 15)
  - Endowment information 2000-2002 (Box 15)
  - Funding and donations 2002-2005 (Box 15)
  - Grants
    - Ann Arbor Community Foundation 2003-2005 (Box 15)
    - Arcus Foundation 2000-2004 (Box 15)
    - Astraea Foundation 2002 (Box 15)
    - Community Foundation for Southeastern Michigan: The Hope Fund
      - 1997 (Box 15)
      - 1997-2001 (Box 15)
      - 1997-2002 (Box 15)
    - David Bohnett Foundation 1999, 2003 (Box 15)
    - FERA
      - Needs assessment evaluation report 2001 (Box 15)
      - Needs assessment survey 2001 (Box 15)
    - Ford grant and AED New Voices fellowship 2002 (Box 15)
      (Contains information about the Ford grant on a floppy disk)
    - Funding Exchange 2003 (Box 15)
    - Gill Foundation
      - 1999-2004 (Box 15)
      - 2002-2003 (Box 15)
    - Gilmour Fund 1999, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Pfizer 2003 (Box 15)
    - SBC
      - 2003 (Box 15)
      - 2004 (Box 15)
  - Matching gifts program 1999-2006 (Box 15)
  - Previous to 1997, 1995-1997; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Reports
    - 2002 (Box 15)
    - 2006 (Box 15)
  - United Way
    - 2001 (Box 15)
    - 2002 (Box 15)
    - 2003 (Box 15)
  - Year end accounting issues 2005 (Box 15)
- Projects
  The Projects (2 linear feet) series collection includes documents relating to various projects of WRAP staff members such as the Gill Foundation's Visibility Project and elements of an un-finished scrapbook. Of note in this series are 11 years of the WRAP-Up newsletter and records documenting the gay rights issues that arose in 2000 as a result of a Boy Scouts of America discriminatory policy, and the subsequent rise of a group called 'scouting for Equality' in Ann Arbor in response to this policy change.
  - Ann Arbor Police Department
    - Dolph Park 2003 (Box 15)
    - Training May-June 2003 (Box 15)
  - Boy Scouts of America (BSA)
    - Ann Arbor City Council regarding United Way and BSA August 2001 (Box 15)
    - District of Columbia Commission on Human Rights 2001 (Box 15)
    - Policy of discrimination November 2000 (Box 15)
    - Scouting for Equality
      - Ann Arbor schools, October 2000-March 2001; 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Ann Arbor schools PTO 2001 (Box 15)
      - Ann Arbor schools and the University of Michigan October 2000-January 2001 (Box 16)
      - City Council resolution January-August 2001 (Box 16)
      - Pamphlet December 2000-February 2001 (Box 16)
      - United Way funding of BSA
        - 2000-2002 (Box 16)
        - 2001 (Box 16)
      - QVIS petition for the University of Michigan to stop aid to United Way, March-October 2001; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Coalition for Adoption Rights Equality (CARE) 2002 (Box 16)
  - Democracy Project-Gill Foundation
    - 2003 (Box 16)
    - List enhancement training and workbook May 2004 (Box 16)
      (Contains information on a CD)
  - Educational information
    - Gay rights articles 1995 (Box 16)
    - "Gay Liberation: When Michigan Tore Out of the Closets and into the Streets," June 1994 (Box 16)
      (written by Tim Retzloff; prepared for the Between The Lines newspaper)
    - How to write a grant proposal-Eastern Michigan University 1998-2001 (Box 16)
    - "Outcast, Miscast, Recast: A documentary history of lesbians and gay men at the University of Michigan," January 1991 (Box 16)
      (written by Tim Retzloff; prepared for the Study Committee on the Status of Lesbians and Gay Men, University of Michigan)
    - University of Michigan SW707 syllabus, Fall 2003 (Box 16)
      (School of Social Work class number 707)
    - Washtenaw County domestic partner benefits 2000 (Box 16)
  - Gay, Lesbian, and Straight Equality Network (GLSEN) 2001-2005 (Box 16)
  - Kerrytown District Association, August 2003(?) (Box 16)
  - Laramie project 2001-2002 (Box 16)
  - Michigan Advocates Exchange, Inc. December 2003 (Box 16)
  - Michigan LGBT timeline 1999 (Box 16)
    (Compiled by Tom Retzloff for the exhibit "Artifacts and Disclosures Michigan's Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Heritage," Harlan Hatcher Graduate Library Main Lobby, The University of Michigan)
  - Michigan Retailers Association application June 2000 (Box 16)
  - Newspaper clippings, 2006(?) (Box 16)
  - Peer counseling and crisis intervention training 2004 (Box 16)
  - Publications
    - Between The Lines -- This week at WRAP clippings 2002 (Box 16)
      (A Michigan LGBT newspaper)
    - WRAP articles 2001-2002 (Box 16)
    - WRAP-Up newsletter
      - 1995-1997 (Volumes 1-3) (Box 16)
      - 1998 (Volume 4) (Box 16)
      - 1999 (Volume 5) (Box 16)
      - 2000 (Volume 6) (Box 16)
      - 2001 (Volume 7) (Box 16)
      - 2002 (Volume 8) (Box 16)
      - 2003 (Volume 9) (Box 16)
      - 2004-2005 (Volume 10-11) (Box 16)
      - Advertising, 2005(?) (Box 17)
      - Member updates June 2004-June 2005 (Box 17)
      - Website 2001-2002 (Box 17)
  - Scrapbook, 2001(?) (Box 17)
  - Toy, Jim
    - Alma campaign 2002 (Box 17)
    - History project January 2003 (Box 17)
    - QVIS caucus, January-March 2001; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Valentines marriage project 2003 (Box 17)
  - Visibility Project 2002 (Box 17)
  - Visibility Project and National Coming Out Day (NCOD) 2002 (Box 17)
  - Youth project, November -- December 2002 (Box 17)
  - Written works
    - "Religion, Disability, and Queerness: A dichotomy," undated (Box 17)
      (written by Magan Rodriguez)
    - Triangle: Building "One Michigan" report February 2003 (Box 17)
      (prepared by Sean Kosofsky for the Governor)
Related Collections
The James W. Toy papers, 1963-2009 at the Bentley Historical Library. Online Finding Aid: http://www.hti.umich.edu/cgi/f/findaid/findaid-idx?c=bhlead&idno=umich-bhl-9744.
The Michigan Campaign for Human Dignity records, 1992-1994 at the Bentley Historical Library. Online Finding Aid http://www.hti.umich.edu/cgi/f/findaid/findaid-idx?c=bhlead&idno=umich-bhl-0099.